<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
 <title>The Sapling devlogs</title>
 <description>The developer logs for the videogame The Sapling, a game about life and evolution</description>
 <link>http://www.thesaplinggame.com</link>
 <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0000</lastBuildDate>
 <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>

  <item>
  <title>Under the hood of the procedural music in The Sapling</title>
  <description>This article is an in-depth interactive explanation of how the procedural music in The Sapling works. Furthermore, we see how I had to give up my preference for clear hummable melodies, but got my way in the end.</description>
  <link>http://www.thesaplinggame.com/devlogs/music</link>
  <guid>http://www.thesaplinggame.com/devlogs/music</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
 </item>
 <item>
  <title>Breakdown of the visual style of The Sapling</title>
  <description>In this article I'll show you how the graphical style of The Sapling is achieved, step by step. At the bottom there's an interactive scene so you can turn all individual effects on and off.</description>
  <link>http://www.thesaplinggame.com/devlogs/visualstyle</link>
  <guid>http://www.thesaplinggame.com/devlogs/visualstyle</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
 </item>
 <item>
  <title>Six 3D models to explain the evolution simulation</title>
  <description>I am releasing six models created by playtesters using the plant and animal builders of The Sapling. Several bodyparts are annotated so you get an idea of how deep the simulation in The Sapling really is.</description>
  <link>http://www.thesaplinggame.com/devlogs/modelsrelease</link>
  <guid>http://www.thesaplinggame.com/devlogs/modelsrelease</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
 </item>
 <item>
  <title>How player content works in The Sapling</title>
  <description>The Sapling was built from the ground up with community interaction in mind. This interaction goes both ways: players can take stuff generated by or for the game, and use it in their own creations, or they can add their own creations to the game. </description>
  <link>http://www.thesaplinggame.com/devlogs/playercontent</link>
  <guid>http://www.thesaplinggame.com/devlogs/playercontent</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
 </item>
 <item>
  <title>The Sapling main theme music available</title>
  <description>In this first devlog I announce the official release of the main theme sheet music, along with the sheet music and its separate layers.</description>
  <link>http://www.thesaplinggame.com/devlogs/musicrelease</link>
  <guid>http://www.thesaplinggame.com/devlogs/musicrelease</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
 </item>


</channel>
</rss>
